Cameron Cooper

Software Engineer

Personal Info

Phone

719.900.8036

E-mail

cameron.w.cooper@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/cameron-cooper-

64bb9247

GitHub

https://www.github.com/cameronwc

WWW

https://cameroncooper.co

Clearance

Top secret interim

Skills

Java - Spring Boot, Junit, Reactive

JavaScript - ES2016, ES2017, ES2018

ReactJS - Redux, Redis

 HTML

CSS - Flexbox, Grid

NodeJS - Express, RESTful API's

Python - openCV, Django

Ruby - Ruby on Rails

mySQL, postgreSQL

MongoDB

Mocha

TDD/BDD

Adobe Photoshop

Linux Administration

AWS - EB, ELB, EC2

Jira

Courses

2018-12 - 2019-01

Advanced Web Developer Bootcamp

2018-06 - 2018-07

AngularJS & NodeJS Bootcamp

2018-03 - 2018-06

Modern React with Redux Bootcamp

2017-10 - 2018-01

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

Results focused Software Engineer with 4 years experience managing clients, working in Agile teams, and coding web applications in ReactJS, Node and Java. Recently finished an internship where I worked on Top Secret projects by securing and improving enterprise applications.

Experience

2019-04 - Software Engineer Intern

2019-12 Polaris Alpha, A Parsons Company

Improved company projects by securing common application vulnerabilities

Wrote Java RESTful back-ends with Spring Boot Improved test coverage of code base with Junit

Created object recognition microservices for images and videos with openCV

2017-12 - CEO / Software Engineer

present Formulated, LLC

20+ completed web design contracts

Improved my clients lead generation coversion rate by 79%

Create Full Stack Web Applications for small businesses that convert users into

customers

URL: https://formulated.design

2016-04 - Software Engineer

2017-01 Battlefield Colorado

Created company website that lead to a 30% increase in lead conversion Created automation programs that improved company efficiency by 22%

Education

2015-08 - University of Colorado Colorado Springs

2019-12 Bachelor's of Innovation™ Computer Security (3.6 GPA) - Business Cross Core

Coursework: Software Engineering, Networks, System Security and Administration, Data Structures, Applied Cryptography, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems,

Entrepreneurship, Innovation

Noteworthy Projects

2019-01 - FORMULATED Project: Pixel Helper

present Software Engineer

An open source image aggregator for Unsplash, Pexels, and other image APIs

Reduced wasted work time by 66%

Production ready / fully tested (Mocha & Chai) NodeJS API Production ready ReactJS front end with daily builds

URL: https://pixelhelper.club

2018-09 - EDU Project: Textbook Swap

2018-12 Team Lead, Software Engineer, Lead Designer

Worked with a team of 4 developers to create a full stack textbook swap application.

Acceptance/Unit tests in Rspec

Coded in Ruby on Rails

URL: https://textbook-swap.herokuapp.com/

2017-10 - PERSONAL Project: Unofficial Yelp API

present Software Engineer

An unofficial Yelp scraper written in Ruby

Capable of harvesting 150+ companies/min from Yelp

Complete with data validation, data cleaning, and reCAPTCHA bypassing